<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Read Rust - Web and Network Services</title><link>https://readrust.net/</link><description>Web and Network Services posts on Read Rust</description><item><title>Rust + Node.js are awesome!</title><link>https://itnext.io/rust-node-js-are-awesome-a50d63411773</link><description>Blazing fast, low requirements, computationally intensive operations on Node.js using Rust</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07825eb3-aaab-46c5-b7e4-680857d73750</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 21:50:20 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Benjamín Calderón</dc:creator></item><item><title>Touring a Fast, Safe, and Complete(ish) Web Service in Rust</title><link>https://brandur.org/rust-web</link><description>For years now, I’ve been having a crisis of faith in interpreted languages. They’re fast and fun to work in at small scale, but when you have a project that gets big, their attractive veneer quickly washes away. A big Ruby or JavaScript (just to name a few) program in production is a never ending game of whack-a-mock – you fix one problem only to find a new one somewhere else. No matter how many tests you write, or how well-disciplined your team, any new development is sure to introduce a stream of bugs that will need to be shored up over the course of months or years.

Central to the problem are the edges. People will reliably do a good job of building and testing the happy paths, but as humans we’re terrible at considering the edge conditions, and it’s those edges and corners that cause trouble over the years that a program is in service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f012379-d71a-4c45-b9db-12c4871070e7</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 14:45:57 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Brandur Leach</dc:creator></item><item><title>Building a Restful CRUD API with Rust</title><link>https://medium.com/sean3z/building-a-restful-crud-api-with-rust-1867308352d8</link><description>Since my initial Node/Rust REST comparison, I’ve wanted to follow up with a comprehensive guide for getting simple CRUD operations up and running in Rust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e32bb679-4afa-48d9-ab51-d589a590348e</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 04:29:33 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Sean Wragg</dc:creator></item><item><title>Multicasting in Rust</title><link>https://bluejekyll.github.io/blog/rust/2018/03/18/multicasting-in-rust.html</link><description>A brief post to help others multicast in Rust</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dae19f32-236c-4329-b26d-e6c47b2631d3</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Benjamin Fry</dc:creator></item><item><title>Building a DNS server in Rust</title><link>https://github.com/EmilHernvall/dnsguide</link><description>With the combined goal of gaining a deep understanding of DNS, of doing something interesting with Rust, and of scratching some of my own itches, I originally set out to implement my own DNS server. This document is not a truthful chronicle of that journey, but rather an idealized version of it, without all the detours I ended up taking. We&apos;ll gradually implement a full DNS server, starting from first principles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44e96573-f8b3-4577-8a76-1cbc8a65ec8b</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Emil Hernvall</dc:creator></item><item><title>Parc3l: Combining Three.js, Rust, and WebAssembly!</title><link>https://medium.com/@cwervo/parc3l-combining-three-js-rust-and-webassembly-c1e643ef7681</link><description>WebAssembly has been interesting me lately, specifically the prospect of doing arithmetically-intensive operations with it, not unlike the fantastic physics engine Emscripten port Ammo.js. Compiling something like that is out of the scope of this little post (but should be getting easier!), and I’ve left some links at the bottom so you can clear more about WebAssembly if you’re interested.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39f186f6-b177-43e6-9b4c-7ffe689926e7</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 14:34:23 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Andres Cuervo</dc:creator></item><item><title>Making WebAssembly better for Rust &amp; for all languages</title><link>https://hacks.mozilla.org/2018/03/making-webassembly-better-for-rust-for-all-languages/</link><description>To be a useful as a web language, Rust needs to work well with the JavaScript ecosystem. We have some work to do to get there, and fortunately that work ...</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf12d6fd-0aea-4d74-b3a7-02a538d210d3</guid><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 15:02:52 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Lin Clark</dc:creator></item><item><title>Crashing a Rust Hyper server with a Denial of Service attack</title><link>https://klausi.github.io/rustnish/2018/03/11/crashing-a-rust-hyper-server-with-a-denial-of-service-attack.html</link><description>I’m writing a reverse proxy in Rust using Hyper and I want to measure performance a bit to know if I’m doing something terribly wrong. By doing that I discovered a Denial of Service vulnerability in Hyper when IO errors are not properly handled. Note that a workaround has been released in the meantime in Hyper 0.11.20, more background info can be found in this Hyper issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d94c5ba-199d-44c2-9148-7a6bbff699d0</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Klaus Purer</dc:creator></item><item><title>Writing a Simple IPFS Crawler</title><link>https://gkbrk.com/2018/03/writing-a-simple-ipfs-crawler/</link><description>IPFS is a peer-to-peer protocol that allows you to access and publish content in a decentralized fashion. It uses hashes to refer to files. Short of someone posting hashes on a website, discoverability of content is pretty low. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;re going to write a very simple crawler for IPFS.
It&amp;rsquo;s challenging to have a traditional search engine in IPFS because content rarely links to each other. But there is another way than just blindly following links like a traditional crawler.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e03aa0e5-bb05-48f0-a4a4-0796d14d1115</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Gökberk Yaltıraklı</dc:creator></item><item><title>Writing servers with Tokio</title><link>https://blog.passcod.name/2018/mar/07/writing-servers-with-tokio</link><description>I’ve been writing a small toy project with Tokio in my spare time’s spare time. I’ll write more about it at a later date. What I’ve found writing it, though, is that there is a specific pattern to writing servers, both UDP and TCP (and presumably others) in Tokio, and it’s not super obvious at first glance. So here it is.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd5790e1-ff4e-4f61-9a8b-05ea774a2e89</guid><pubDate>Wed,  7 Mar 2018 09:35:30 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Félix Saparelli</dc:creator></item><item><title>Writing a Microservice in Rust</title><link>http://www.goldsborough.me/rust/web/tutorial/2018/01/20/17-01-11-writing_a_microservice_in_rust/</link><description>Let me begin this article on Writing a Microservice in Rust by talking about C++. I’ve been a reasonably active member of the C++ community for quite a while now, attending and contributing talks to conferences, following the development and evangelism of the language’s more modern features and of course writing lots of it. C++ is a language that gives its users very fine-grained control over all aspects of the program they are writing, at the cost of a steep learning curve and a large body of knowledge required to write effective C++. However, C++ is also a very old language, conceived by Bjarne Stroustrup in 1985, and thus caries a lot of technical debt even into modern standards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">776dd5f1-c6d0-48da-8e0a-6fcae00fb923</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Peter Goldsborough</dc:creator></item><item><title>Speed Without Wizardry</title><link>http://fitzgeraldnick.com/2018/02/26/speed-without-wizardry.html</link><description>Vyacheslav Egorov, who goes by mraleph on the Web, wrote a response to my article “Oxidizing Source Maps with Rust and WebAssembly” titled “Maybe you don’t need Rust and WASM to speed up your JS”.

The “Oxidizing” article recounts my experience integrating Rust (compiled to WebAssembly) into the source-map JavaScript library. Although the JavaScript implementation was originally authored in idiomatic JavaScript style, as we profiled and implemented speed improvements, the code became hard to read and maintain. With Rust and its zero-cost abstractions, we found that there was no trade-off between performance and clean code.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26bc7432-d561-4e1f-8cf2-2c30b8ac63ab</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:creator>Nick Fitzgerald</dc:creator></item><item><title>Recently, for a Rusty Web</title><link>http://seanmonstar.com/post/171170905822/recently-for-a-rusty-web</link><description>It’s been a few months since I shifted my focus full time to Rust, and in that time, we’ve gotten a lot of work done! I wanted to update you here what all that is, since it’s spread around on multiple repositories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d134e6-ddc6-4571-965c-4b6e72a544eb</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Sean McArthur</dc:creator></item><item><title>Porting Rust to WebAssembly</title><link>https://udoprog.github.io/rust/2018-02-19/porting-rust-to-wasm.html</link><description>I recently spent some effort trying to make reproto run in a browser. Here I want to outline the problems I encountered and how I worked around them. I will also provide a number of suggestions for how things might be improved for future porters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b97498f-3ffb-4c89-8973-c2beb5e0140e</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>John-John Tedro</dc:creator></item><item><title>Fanta: An opinionated framework for web development in rust</title><link>https://github.com/trezm/Fanta</link><description>Fanta is a web framework that aims for developers to be productive and consistent across projects and teams. Its goals are to be: Opinionated, Fast, and Intuitive. Based heavily off of the work here: https://github.com/tokio-rs/tokio-minihttp</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0af4c90e-74b2-438d-aaed-798c9f6e900a</guid><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 18:44:00 +1100</pubDate><dc:creator>Peter Mertz</dc:creator></item><item><title>Gameland intro, reimplemented in Rust for WebAssembly</title><link>http://perlun.eu.org/en/programming/gameland/</link><description>My nice brother Johannes Ridderstedt sent me some old files a few weeks ago (in late 2017), stuff that he had preserved from an age-old computer of ours. One of these was the file named gameland.zip (not published yet, but I might put it up here some day.) I managed to get this running, and liked what I saw (you&apos;ll find the YouTube link to it further down on this page.) Around this time I was reading a bit about WebAssembly which I think will redefine and help reshape the web as we see it today. I was also looking at the Hello, Rust web page, and the &quot;FizzleFade effect using a Feistel network&quot; page in particular.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86b2dfcd-a01d-47e1-acb8-2ddbca20db62</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 07:44:00 +1100</pubDate><dc:creator>Per Lundberg</dc:creator></item><item><title>Event Sourcing with Aggregates in Rust</title><link>https://medium.com/@KevinHoffman/event-sourcing-with-aggregates-in-rust-4022af41cf67</link><description>Everyone loves event sourcing, right up until the moment they have to implement it. At that moment all the wonderful whiteboard drawings…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbc46982-1321-4e4e-8d9f-344963341c21</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 15:11:08 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Kevin Hoffman</dc:creator></item><item><title>Deploying A Rust Server to Google App Engine with Travis CI &amp; Docker</title><link>https://medium.com/@gallantmrgn/deploying-rust-server-to-google-app-engine-with-travis-ci-docker-b80acfce2ce5</link><description>I woke up this morning with one goal: to convert my website (morgangallant.com) into a Rust web server. I have been a long time fan of…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b698c99-99e0-4fad-8716-b58dbd9c255c</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 00:07:43 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Morgan A. Gallant</dc:creator></item><item><title>A Wee Allocator for WebAssembly</title><link>http://fitzgeraldnick.com/2018/02/09/wee-alloc.html</link><description>Introducing wee_alloc. wee_alloc is a work-in-progress memory allocator designed for WebAssembly. It has a tiny code size footprint, compiling down to only a kilobyte of .wasm code.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b542e90-1f02-4368-90e4-a1931ccf1935</guid><pubDate>Fri,  9 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:creator>Nick Fitzgerald</dc:creator></item><item><title>I rewrote a Nintendo emulator with Rust / WebAssembly (Japanese)</title><link>http://blog.bokuweb.me/entry/2018/02/08/101522</link><description>概要 以前、JSで書いた(ファミコンのエミュレータを書いた - undefined)ファミコンのエミュレータをRustで書き直してみた。 また、技術的な内容はQiitaの方にも書いているので興味のある方は参照してみてください。(まだ Hello, World!までしか書けてませんが。) qiita.com もともとファミコンのエミュレータって新しい言語を習得するのにちょうどいい題材だったりするのでは、って話しからスタートしてて、よくわからないのでJSで書いてみて、ようやくRustで一通りは実装できた感じ。まだバグや未実装（音声周りやマッパー）も多いんですが、ひとまずはお腹いっぱいな感じ。 成果…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6347974-c84a-438a-924a-52ef37f6c99a</guid><pubDate>Thu,  8 Feb 2018 10:15:22 +0900</pubDate><dc:creator>bokuweb</dc:creator></item><item><title>DataFusion: Big Data Platform for Rust</title><link>https://www.datafusion.rs/</link><description>DataFusion is an open-source Big Data platform implemented in the Rust programming language with a similar programming style to Apache Spark.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">434c400b-b4ac-49c9-87fa-db2a8b5f1ba7</guid><pubDate>Sun,  4 Feb 2018 16:51:47 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Andy Grove</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust and WebAssembly with Turtle - /var/blog</title><link>https://varblog.org/blog/2018/01/08/rust-and-webassembly-with-turtle/</link><description>In this post, I&apos;ll walk through a few of the highlights of getting Turtle, a Rust library for creating animated drawings, to run in the browser with WebAssembly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c8f0581-5b1d-485b-852c-83c0deef73d5</guid><pubDate>Mon,  8 Jan 2018 09:54:00 -0600</pubDate><dc:creator>Marshall Pierce</dc:creator></item></channel></rss>