<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Read Rust - Community</title><link>https://readrust.net/</link><description>Community posts on Read Rust</description><item><title>An Open Source SDK and Serde Magic: My First Two Months as a Member of the Rust Community</title><link>https://hackernoon.com/an-open-source-sdk-and-serde-magic-my-first-two-months-as-a-member-of-the-rust-community-333444af761e</link><description><![CDATA[So why Rust? After all, using languages like Ruby, Go, or JavaScript, I could have written numerous full stack applications at this point. Why worry about types and ownership and all that nonsense?

Well in Rust, there are certain safety guarantees… yes, you know, the typical spiel. That may have been enough to interest me in rust, but it was not the reason I decided to stick with it — ultimately what drew me in was the community.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f740b1f-622f-4a43-a46c-6a0a13818292</guid><pubDate>Wed,  9 May 2018 14:28:15 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Robert Durst</dc:creator></item><item><title>Madrid GNOME+Rust Hackfest, part 2</title><link>https://people.gnome.org/~federico/blog/madrid-gnome-rust-2.html</link><description><![CDATA[Hacking on gnome-class continues apace! Philippe updated our dependencies. Alberto made the syntax for per-instance private structsmore ergonomic, and then made that code nice and compact. Martin improved our conversion from CamelCase to snake_case for code generation. Daniel added initial support for GObject properties. This is not finished...; ]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a1ac912-0af7-47cb-b540-1cb3efc46956</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 08:59:23 +0200</pubDate><dc:creator>Federico Mena Quintero</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust+GNOME Hackfest in Madrid</title><link>https://blog.guillaume-gomez.fr/articles/2018-04-21+Rust%2BGNOME+Hackfest+in+Madrid</link><description><![CDATA[Last week was the third edition of the Rust+GNOME hackfest. What about talking a bit about what we achieved? The goals of this edition were: Improve gnome-class, improve gtk-rs continuous integration process, improve gtk-rs crates bindings. I'm happy to say that we were able to achieve all of these goals!]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">86f4fa21-5194-4439-a131-85c3a587a1fd</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Guillaume Gomez</dc:creator></item><item><title>Madrid GNOME+Rust Hackfest, part 1</title><link>https://people.gnome.org/~federico/blog/madrid-gnome-rust-1.html</link><description><![CDATA[I'm in Madrid since Monday, at the third GNOME+Rust hackfest! The OpenShine folks are kindly letting us use their offices, on the seventh floor of a building by the Cuatro Caminos roundabout.

I am very, very thankful that this time everyone seems to be working on developing gnome-class. It's a difficult project for me, and more brainpower is definitely welcome — all the indirection, type conversion, GObject obscurity, and procedural macro shenanigans definitely take a toll on oneself.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">53831192-f7e2-4841-898f-f39f1cd9f1ff</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 02:55:12 -0500</pubDate><dc:creator>Federico Mena Quintero</dc:creator></item><item><title>Increasing Rust’s Reach 2018</title><link>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2018/04/02/Increasing-Rusts-Reach-2018.html</link><description><![CDATA[The Rust team is happy to announce that we’re running our Increasing Rust’s Reach program again this year. Increasing Rust’s Reach is one of several programs run by the project to grow Rust’s community of project collaborators and leaders.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">b525113d-ce0a-4c11-b4d1-553eb3fef88d</guid><pubDate>Mon,  2 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Ashley Williams</dc:creator></item></channel></rss>