<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Read Rust - Community</title><link>https://readrust.net/</link><description>Community posts on Read Rust</description><item><title>Localizing the Rust Website to Traditional Chinese</title><link>https://medium.com/coding-neutrino-blog/localize-the-rust-website-to-traditional-chinese-473413f44d21</link><description><![CDATA[I am glad to announce that the Traditional Chinese (正體中文) version of the Rust official website has been launched. Thanks to all contributors in the community. This article records our experience to achieve the work.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">52f43349-8161-4996-95ad-138528adcf21</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 16:38:55 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Liu An Chi (tigercosmos)</dc:creator></item><item><title>timetill.rs: highlighting all the Rust conferences around the world</title><link>https://timetill.rs/</link><description><![CDATA[timetill.rs is a community project focused on highlighting all the Rust conferences around the world. Timetill.rs is an open project that anyone in the community can contribute to.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">eecb5f26-323a-4d45-8a03-4fef1b0943e0</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>XAMPPRocky</dc:creator></item><item><title>Status of rust-analyzer: Achievements and Open Collective</title><link>https://ferrous-systems.com/blog/rust-analyzer-status-opencollective/</link><description><![CDATA[rust-analyzer is an experimental compiler frontend for the Rust programming language. The ultimate goal for this project is to provide the perfect IDE experience for Rust, with all IDE features working flawlessly while editing code. This post talks about what happened to rust-analyzer in between the all-hands and today, discusses future plans, and also announces the rust-analyzer Open Collective.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">09564ee8-19af-4b03-95c4-b231ffd7f24f</guid><pubDate>Mon,  1 Jul 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Aleksey Kladov</dc:creator></item><item><title>Announcing The Triage WG</title><link>https://users.rust-lang.org/t/announcing-the-triage-wg/28909</link><description><![CDATA[The Release team is pleased to announce the triage working group , which will assume responsibility from the release team for triaging issues and pull requests in the rust-lang repositories as well as for diagnosing failures in Crater runs.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">254cd239-bad6-4331-ad8e-fe00edfb834d</guid><pubDate>Mon,  3 Jun 2019 16:15:03 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Dylan DPC</dc:creator></item><item><title>The Governance WG is going public</title><link>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2019/06/03/governance-wg-announcement.html</link><description><![CDATA[Hey all! Today we're happy to announce the Governance Working Group is going public. We've been spending the last couple weeks finding our bearings and structuring the working group.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">d325b708-16d9-45b7-a1d8-6f9e5a331da5</guid><pubDate>Mon,  3 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>The Rust Governance WG</dc:creator></item><item><title>The 2019 Rust Event Lineup</title><link>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2019/05/20/The-2019-Rust-Event-Lineup.html</link><description><![CDATA[We're excited for the 2019 conference season, which we're actually late in writing up. Some incredible events have already happened! Read on to learn more about all the events occurring around the world, past and future.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c93aa16-acee-46d1-8a08-462d9ce7c09f</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Rust Community Team</dc:creator></item><item><title>✩ The RustBridge Roadmap for 2019</title><link>https://marisa.cloud/phame/live/1/post/1/the_rustbridge_roadmap_for_2019/</link><description><![CDATA[This is less a specific roadmap and more of a rough braindump of where I think the project currently stands and where I would personally like it to head in 2019 and beyond. With that, let's get started: The main thing I would like to focus on this year is clearing community debt. I don't actually know what you would call this, but it's sort of like technical debt, just manifested within communities.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">de6a9110-16fb-47df-a80d-f63af3033589</guid><pubDate>Thu,  2 May 2019 10:19:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>olivia</dc:creator></item><item><title>A close touch with Rust community</title><link>https://medium.com/@Aimeedeer/a-close-touch-with-rust-community-4a8507b756d9</link><description><![CDATA[About RustCon Asia 2019：There was definitely a little bit of everything for everyone attended. It was heartwarming to see people enjoying their experience from talks and at the same time meeting new and old friends. The portion of the attendees was just beginning with Rust benefited from talks such as Olivia’s RustBridge for beginners, Nick’s thinking in Rust and Alex’s How to learn Rust efficiently.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">00aea687-4bba-48e5-8568-000ef44a419e</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 11:49:07 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Aimee Z</dc:creator></item><item><title>Design Space Map</title><link>https://llogiq.github.io/2019/04/23/map.html</link><description><![CDATA[The Rust community currently appears to reconfigure its design process. There is some discussion around RFCs. A topic that comes up is shared summaries. I think this is a great idea and want to share my 2¢ here.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">a436e872-4c6f-4b9a-a311-eb7658d23cb2</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Llogiq</dc:creator></item><item><title>AiC: Collaborative summary documents</title><link>http://smallcultfollowing.com/babysteps/blog/2019/04/22/aic-collaborative-summary-documents/</link><description><![CDATA[One of the challenges I see with how we often do design is that this “solution space” is actually quite implicit. We are exploring it through comments, but each comment is only tracing out one path through the terrain. I wanted to see if we could try to represent the solution space explicitly. This post is a kind of “experience report” on one such experiment, what I am calling a collaborative summary document (in contrast to the more standard summary comment that we often do).]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">e335233d-84ab-4f50-9cc0-5e401a6b5363</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><dc:creator>Niko Matsakis</dc:creator></item><item><title>AiC: Adventures in consensus</title><link>http://smallcultfollowing.com/babysteps/blog/2019/04/19/aic-adventures-in-consensus/</link><description><![CDATA[In the talk I gave at Rust LATAM, I said that the Rust project has always emphasized finding the best solution, rather than winning the argument. I think this is one of our deepest values. It’s also one of the hardest for us to uphold.

Let’s face it – when you’re having a conversation, it’s easy to get attached to specific proposals. It’s easy to have those proposals change from “Option A” vs “Option B” to “my option” and “their option”. Once this happens, it can be very hard to let them “win” – even if you know that both options are quite reasonable.

This is a problem I’ve been thinking a lot about lately. So I wanted to start an irregular series of blog posts entitled “Adventures in consensus”, or AiC for short. These posts are my way of exploring the topic, and hopefully getting some feedback from all of you while I’m at it.

This first post dives into what a phrase like “finding the best solution” even means (is there a best?) as well as the mechanics of how one might go about deciding if you really have the “best” solution. Along the way, we’ll see a few places where I think our current process could do better.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">00b32f85-009b-464f-8e31-c9930a0b67f3</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><dc:creator>Niko Matsakis</dc:creator></item><item><title>Moving on from Rails and what&apos;s next</title><link>https://blog.seantheprogrammer.com/moving-on-from-rails-and-whats-next</link><description><![CDATA[It’s been more than 6 years since my first commit to Ruby on Rails. I had just gotten my first full time Ruby position, was excited to move away from PHP, and wanted to give back. Since then I made 1452 commits to the project. Today, I am finally ready to move on from Rails.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">94f04f9a-9a74-4e3c-9d96-02fec8e01229</guid><pubDate>Tue,  2 Apr 2019 11:43:23 -0700</pubDate><dc:creator>Sean Griffin</dc:creator></item><item><title>Governance Working Group announcement</title><link>https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/governance-working-group-announcement/9637</link><description><![CDATA[I’m very excited to announce the formation of the Governance working group, an offspring of the Core team. The high-level goal of the group is making the workings of the Rust project more predictable and transparent. The working group will examine, document, and propose improvements to some of the policies and procedures that we use to run the project. To that end, the Governance WG will take multiple viewpoints and investigate our current modes of working under the perspective of community members and project members alike. Our aim is to make the project more transparent and also make it easier for interested community members to give effective feedback and stay close to the project.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc9cf1b6-7814-4a3a-9e3e-adcd17835a81</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 16:01:23 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Florian Gilcher</dc:creator></item><item><title>thank u, next</title><link>https://words.steveklabnik.com/thank-u-next</link><description><![CDATA[I started working at 15, when I took a job as a pizza cook. Over the next seven years, I moved up the ranks, to a driver, shift manager, and then as part of the “new store opening team.” The franchise was growing, and we needed to help new franchisees open their new stores. I’d travel to where the new store was a week before they would open, help train the new staff, and then work their opening weekend. It was really fulfilling work; if pizza paid as well as tech, I’d seriously consider doing it forever.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec95e248-cef0-42ed-8a49-8e03d8c7e30b</guid><pubDate>Tue,  8 Jan 2019 01:10:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Steve Klabnik</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust Raps - Ferris Crab (Rust Raps 2018 Edition)</title><link>http://fitzgeraldnick.com/2018/12/13/rust-raps.html</link><description><![CDATA[Just released: the hot new single “Ferris Crab (Rust Raps 2018 Edition)” by Rusta Rhymes off their upcoming debut album impl Drop for Mic {}.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">733eb57b-95f6-490b-b3aa-ba223cacb0f5</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate><dc:creator>Rusta Rhymes</dc:creator></item><item><title>Positive-Sum Games</title><link>https://llogiq.github.io/2018/12/11/sum.html</link><description><![CDATA[One thing I learned from Aaron Turon is to search for positive-sum games. First what does that even mean? In most arguments you may run into, it will be easy to find a zero-sum game: Your win is my loss and vice versa. However, in many situations, it is actually possible to go above those petty games and find a variant that allows us both to win.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fdb4722-43ce-4bad-b37e-67dae34eecb2</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Llogiq</dc:creator></item><item><title>Thessaloniki GNOME+Rust Hackfest 2018</title><link>https://people.gnome.org/~federico/blog/thessaloniki-gnome-rust-2018.html</link><description><![CDATA[A couple of weeks ago we had the fourth GNOME+Rust hackfest, this time in Thessaloniki, Greece.  We held the hackfest at the CoHo coworking space, a small, cozy office between the University and the sea. Every such hackfest I am overwhelmed by the kind hackers who work on [gnome-class], the code generator for GObject implementations in Rust.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">7828aada-388f-4b7b-bac1-24de2e65cf6a</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 17:37:31 -0600</pubDate><dc:creator>Federico Mena Quintero</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust+GNOME Hackfest #4</title><link>http://antoyo.ml/rust-gnome-hackfest-thessaloniki</link><description><![CDATA[Less than 2 weeks ago, I was working on improving the integration of Rust with GNOME libraries at the fourth Hackfest, which happened this time in Thessaloniki.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9feb6f2-ba42-42ca-a0a3-dc37f4ce69ff</guid><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Antoni Boucher</dc:creator></item><item><title>My Experience in Increasing Rust&apos;s Reach 2018</title><link>https://rahul-thakoor.github.io/my-experience-in-increasing-rusts-reach-2018/</link><description><![CDATA[I recently had the privilege of participating the Increasing Rust’s Reach(IRR) program. The program aims to grow Rust’s community of project collaborators and leaders. Increasing Rust’s Reach brings together Rust team members and individuals who are underrepresented in Rust’s community and the tech industry for a partnership of three (3) months, from mid-May to mid-August. Each partnership agrees to a commitment of 3–5 hours per week working on a Rust Project.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">04d63d37-82e6-4076-a90f-ef0a20945316</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 08:49:37 +0400</pubDate><dc:creator>Rahul Thakoor</dc:creator></item><item><title>Anatomy Of a Great Rust Blog</title><link>http://www.wezm.net/technical/2018/08/anatomy-of-a-great-rust-blog/</link><description><![CDATA[I've posted 718 articles to Read Rust. This post shares some insights I've gleaned from them, to make your posts as readable and discoverable as possible.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">09da227e-6517-48db-ae3f-90f1d1086731</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 06:17:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Wesley Moore</dc:creator></item><item><title>Ideas for Rust Meetups</title><link>https://llogiq.github.io/2018/08/08/meetup-ideas.html</link><description><![CDATA[Since I’m co-organizing the Rhein-Main Rust meetup (and am probably the main driving force behind it), I tought, it might be useful to share a few ideas we have that we have either already done, or plan doing – perhaps other meetup organizers can benefit from this. Note that our meetups usually run 2-4 hours, but some attendees may have to join late or leave early so the format has to take this into account.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cf7d62c-c8d9-4116-ae4c-7ac155d015cb</guid><pubDate>Wed,  8 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Llogiq</dc:creator></item><item><title>Sustainability</title><link>https://yakshav.es/sustainability/</link><description><![CDATA[I’m at a fork again: my FOSS project responsibilities have grown so much that they encroach on other parts of my life. This includes time I should spend with company, clients and personal live. It leaves me with two options: shed many of my projects (as mxsash does) or find ways of making this more sustainable. Retreating would also mean that on the surviving projects, others would have to cover the resulting gap, often with less skills or experience.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e7e0d63-d08d-4b38-812b-d67b5b7f9d43</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Florian Gilcher</dc:creator></item><item><title>Musing About Communities Size And Activity</title><link>https://ervin.ipsquad.net/2018/06/22/musing-about-communities-size-and-activity/</link><description><![CDATA[I wanted to take a very quick peak at Rust. It's very different from our previous cases, no application or frameworks in the traditional sense but a language. It seems very popular toward developers using it, I'm personally interested in it hence why it is in that post.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">85a6b729-6bb3-4dc0-9a15-80ba9ff44f68</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 19:36:00 +0200</pubDate><dc:creator>Kevin Ottens</dc:creator></item><item><title>Increasing Rust&apos;s Reach 2018 Prticipants</title><link>http://reach.rust-lang.org/2018/participants</link><description><![CDATA[This year's class of Increasing Rust's Reach participants span 9 timezones and 11 countries. 64% are non-native English speakers, and the group, as a whole, represents fluency in 14+ languages. We're super excited to welcome them to the Rust community!]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d48fc36-98e0-46ee-8c2d-d2d586770ab9</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>The Rust Community Team</dc:creator></item><item><title>Listening and trust, part 3</title><link>http://aturon.github.io/2018/06/18/listening-part-3/</link><description><![CDATA[In this this post in the listening and trust series, I’m going to talk through one of the most intense discussions the Rust community has had: the module system changes that were part of last year’s ergonomics initiative.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">c81413e6-7dc3-4a06-95dc-846a2cfa268a</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Aaron Turon</dc:creator></item><item><title>Design Guideline Problem Statement</title><link>https://vorner.github.io/2018/06/10/design-guideline-problem-statement.html</link><description><![CDATA[There were some heated discussions in Rust community as of late. During that discussions, I argued that some best practices for RFC authors would improve both on the results as well as the discussions and I promised to give it a try.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">afe4d926-caf9-4709-95f0-3bf0249b60e2</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Michal &apos;vorner&apos; Vaner</dc:creator></item><item><title>Sponsor work on Rust!</title><link>http://aturon.github.io/sponsor/</link><description><![CDATA[This page is a first attempt at facilitating sponsorship. This is not an officially endorsed list, but it is a list of Rustaceans that I have personally vetted and sponsored, and encourage you to support. Each of them has a long, public history of impactful work in the community.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">16518cb2-ca9f-4b67-b4d3-bc9042a23ea2</guid><pubDate>Wed,  6 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Aaron Turon</dc:creator></item><item><title>Listening and trust, part 2</title><link>http://aturon.github.io/2018/06/02/listening-part-2/</link><description><![CDATA[In the previous post in this series, I recounted an early lesson for the Rust Core Team about working in the open. In this post, I want to talk about the delicate interplay between listening and trust when doing design in the open.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8e154fc-96f0-4c63-99fb-ba62c7cc689f</guid><pubDate>Sat,  2 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Aaron Turon</dc:creator></item><item><title>My Rust Story</title><link>https://ricky.hosfelt.io/blog/rust_reach.html</link><description><![CDATA[With #RustReach starting soon I have ran into a few "My Rust Story" posts. My path to Rust certainly is not typical (I studied HR Management in undergrad…).

The journey really started for me back in middle/high school as I was very interested in video games, computers, and how things worked. So with a few friends started a computer repair "business" that serviced the local (Western Pennsylvania) area. By the time my sophomore year of highschool rolled around we had lined up a few of the parents who owned local businesses/churches and were doing some pretty serious consulting/maintenance for our ages (also installing Halo and Half-life 2: Deathmatch on the school's servers...).]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">469533e2-7193-41b3-a754-adb5281e276f</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Ricky Hosfelt</dc:creator></item><item><title>Listening and trust, part 1</title><link>http://aturon.github.io/2018/05/25/listening-part-1/</link><description><![CDATA[For me, most weeks working on Rust are fun — exhilarating, even. But, just like with anything else, some weeks are hard.

As this week draws to a close, I feel troubled. On the one hand, things are looking strong for the 2018 Edition (which I want to write more about soon). But on the other hand, this week I locked two RFC threads, flagged a bunch of comments for moderation, and generally absorbed a lot of emotion from a lot of different quarters of the community. There’s a sense of simmering distrust.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e49045f-dc48-4471-bc83-353183d6c4f8</guid><pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Aaron Turon</dc:creator></item><item><title>A shared, mutable ecosystem</title><link>https://kodraus.github.io/rust/2018/05/23/a-shared-mutable-ecosystem.html</link><description><![CDATA[Ownership is a fundamental piece of Rust’s story. It amounts to a tight set of rules about who owns a value in a program, how that value can be aliased and mutated, and when that value is dropped. It prevents shared mutable state, which is the root cause of major bugs in software written without the same guarantees.

In this post I’d like to talk about a different kind ownership in though. I’d like to talk about ownership of libraries in the Rust ecosystem and the problem of sustainable maintainership.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1fd2a84-e451-4299-9327-eb39f3a1ca8f</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 21:49:12 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Ashley Mannix</dc:creator></item><item><title>How I got into rust</title><link>https://liv.cat/how-i-got-into-rust</link><description><![CDATA[There’s currently a campaign around the #RustReach program where it’s people post their, uh, Rust “origin stories”, so to say. Mine is not nearly as long as some other peoples’, but I thought I’d try my hand at this regardless.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">9626a0ad-d7d5-4b09-b642-a273b535504f</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>liv hugger</dc:creator></item><item><title>My Rust Story</title><link>https://llogiq.github.io/2018/05/15/story.html</link><description><![CDATA[The #rustreach project is apparently asking people how they got into Rust, and though I wasn’t asked in person, I thought it may be useful to write down my personal Rust story. Here goes nothing.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">197e6f6d-ecff-4682-8a91-fff94f38fc7a</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Llogiq</dc:creator></item><item><title>My Pathway to Outreachy with Mozilla</title><link>https://medium.com/women-who-code-delhi/my-pathway-to-outreachy-with-mozilla-ede312b08efd</link><description><![CDATA[I first heard about Outreachy from my coach last year when I was applying for Rails Girls Summer of Code (RGSoC). Although we didn’t make through RGSoC at that time, I learned a lot about how Open Source works; whether it was about learning intricacies of Git, building patience to figure out a bug among thousands of lines of code, or becoming a programmer with better problem-solving and communication skills.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ff4bfa8-5426-47a6-9761-3f9c4f090a61</guid><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 05:54:12 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Kanika Saini</dc:creator></item><item><title>On the origin of rustaceans</title><link>https://quietmisdreavus.net/code/2018/05/11/on-the-origin-of-rustaceans/</link><description><![CDATA[The “Increasing Rust’s Reach” projects are kicking off! With it, the Community Team is asking for people to describe how they contribute to Rust, to demonstrate the breadth of talent and perspective in the community. So here’s my personal Rust story!]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">61b70d34-71d7-4258-b8f2-f3c2cadce508</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 13:30:00 -0500</pubDate><dc:creator>QuietMisdreavus</dc:creator></item><item><title>Increasing Rust&apos;s Reach Kickoff</title><link>https://mgattozzi.com/rust-reach-kickoff</link><description><![CDATA[I have the great pleasure and privilege this year to be one of the mentors for Increasing Rust's Reach. I'll be working with Sarah and nano on WebAssembly and I'm really excited to see what we accomplish over the next few months. Even after our first meeting I just know they're gonna do some great things. Over the coming months I'll be documenting their progress, but to kick things off the Rust Community team is asking people to describe their story and how they contribute to Rust, to show off the variety and breadth of our experiences and talent in a wide variety of areas. This is my story.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">842d15e6-6102-45a0-905c-6a25995f8dc9</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Michael Gattozzi</dc:creator></item><item><title>An Open Source SDK and Serde Magic: My First Two Months as a Member of the Rust Community</title><link>https://hackernoon.com/an-open-source-sdk-and-serde-magic-my-first-two-months-as-a-member-of-the-rust-community-333444af761e</link><description><![CDATA[So why Rust? After all, using languages like Ruby, Go, or JavaScript, I could have written numerous full stack applications at this point. Why worry about types and ownership and all that nonsense?

Well in Rust, there are certain safety guarantees… yes, you know, the typical spiel. That may have been enough to interest me in rust, but it was not the reason I decided to stick with it — ultimately what drew me in was the community.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f740b1f-622f-4a43-a46c-6a0a13818292</guid><pubDate>Wed,  9 May 2018 14:28:15 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Robert Durst</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust+GNOME Hackfest in Madrid</title><link>https://blog.guillaume-gomez.fr/articles/2018-04-21+Rust%2BGNOME+Hackfest+in+Madrid</link><description><![CDATA[Last week was the third edition of the Rust+GNOME hackfest. What about talking a bit about what we achieved? The goals of this edition were: Improve gnome-class, improve gtk-rs continuous integration process, improve gtk-rs crates bindings. I'm happy to say that we were able to achieve all of these goals!]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">86f4fa21-5194-4439-a131-85c3a587a1fd</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Guillaume Gomez</dc:creator></item><item><title>Madrid GNOME+Rust Hackfest, part 2</title><link>https://people.gnome.org/~federico/blog/madrid-gnome-rust-2.html</link><description><![CDATA[Hacking on gnome-class continues apace! Philippe updated our dependencies. Alberto made the syntax for per-instance private structsmore ergonomic, and then made that code nice and compact. Martin improved our conversion from CamelCase to snake_case for code generation. Daniel added initial support for GObject properties. This is not finished...; ]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a1ac912-0af7-47cb-b540-1cb3efc46956</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 08:59:23 +0200</pubDate><dc:creator>Federico Mena Quintero</dc:creator></item><item><title>Madrid GNOME+Rust Hackfest, part 1</title><link>https://people.gnome.org/~federico/blog/madrid-gnome-rust-1.html</link><description><![CDATA[I'm in Madrid since Monday, at the third GNOME+Rust hackfest! The OpenShine folks are kindly letting us use their offices, on the seventh floor of a building by the Cuatro Caminos roundabout.

I am very, very thankful that this time everyone seems to be working on developing gnome-class. It's a difficult project for me, and more brainpower is definitely welcome — all the indirection, type conversion, GObject obscurity, and procedural macro shenanigans definitely take a toll on oneself.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">53831192-f7e2-4841-898f-f39f1cd9f1ff</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 02:55:12 -0500</pubDate><dc:creator>Federico Mena Quintero</dc:creator></item><item><title>Increasing Rust’s Reach 2018</title><link>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2018/04/02/Increasing-Rusts-Reach-2018.html</link><description><![CDATA[The Rust team is happy to announce that we’re running our Increasing Rust’s Reach program again this year. Increasing Rust’s Reach is one of several programs run by the project to grow Rust’s community of project collaborators and leaders.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">b525113d-ce0a-4c11-b4d1-553eb3fef88d</guid><pubDate>Mon,  2 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Ashley Williams</dc:creator></item></channel></rss>