<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Read Rust - Crates</title><link>https://readrust.net/</link><description>Crates posts on Read Rust</description><item><title>Corona: If you want to get async out out of your way</title><link>https://vorner.github.io/corona-04.html</link><description>For some time now I develop a Rust library for asynchronous programming with coroutines, called Corona (note there’s a version 0.4.0-pre.1, but Crates prefer the „stable“ 0.3.1). I believe it is starting to be useful, so I wrote this description to show what it is good for and how it fits into the big picture of Rust. There’ll be some more changes, though, at least because Tokio just released a new version (and Futures plan to do so soon), so Corona will have to adapt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">019b1da3-b979-478b-89ed-7824c75df122</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 19:51:00 +1100</pubDate><dc:creator>Michal &apos;vorner&apos; Vaner</dc:creator></item><item><title>Combine 3 - Partial parsing in Rust</title><link>https://marwes.github.io/2018/02/08/combine-3.html</link><description>Combine is a parser combinator library for the Rust programming language. I first announced version 3 of Combine back in August and back then I definitely expected to have a stable version by now. However other projects (cough gluon cough) got in the way and Combine fell to the wayside. It didn’t help that I didn’t have a killer feature for 3.0 either, user-defined error types make it possible to define parsers usable in #[no_std] crates which is great when you need it but it is still a fairly niche use-case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29eb1ede-d551-4b8d-aeec-c673aafb7e8f</guid><pubDate>Thu,  8 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Markus Westerlind</dc:creator></item><item><title>Tokio Reform is Shipped and the Road to 0.2</title><link>https://tokio.rs/blog/2018-02-tokio-reform-shipped/</link><description>I&apos;m happy to announce that today, the changes proposed in the reform RFC have been released to crates.io as tokio 0.1. The primary changes are: Add a default global event loop, eliminating the need for setting up and managing your own event loop in the vast majority of cases, and decouple all task execution functionality from Tokio.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0a2bc9c-effa-4859-b804-cbe839060855</guid><pubDate>Wed,  7 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Carl Lerche</dc:creator></item><item><title>Criterion.rs v0.2 - a statistics-driven benchmarking library for Rust</title><link>https://bheisler.github.io/post/criterion-rs-0-2/</link><description>Criterion.rs is a statistics-driven benchmarking library for Rust. It provides precise measurements of changes in the performance of benchmarked code, and gives strong statistical confidence that apparent performance changes are real and not simply noise. Clear output, a simple API and reasonable defaults make it easy to use even for developers without a background in statistics. Unlike the benchmarking harness provided by Rust, Criterion.rs can be used with stable versions of the compiler.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e5df82f-aba3-4832-bbe6-e995b2e544ef</guid><pubDate>Mon,  5 Feb 2018 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate><dc:creator>Brook Heisler</dc:creator></item><item><title>Faster Progress Report 2</title><link>https://adamniederer.com/blog/faster-pr-2.html</link><description>faster began as a yak shave, created to aid base💯 in its quest to become the fastest meme on Github. Writing an explicit AVX2-accelerated version of base💯&apos;s encoder and decoder, then realizing I&apos;d have to do the same thing again to see the speedups on my Ivy Bridge desktop, pushed me to make this library. Months later, it has blossomed into its own project, and has eclipsed base💯 in both popularity and promise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1a29851-ab4c-4739-a41f-56e9c783f5e4</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 22:14:41 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Adam Niederer</dc:creator></item></channel></rss>