<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Read Rust - Rust 2020</title><link>https://readrust.net/</link><description>Rust 2020 posts on Read Rust</description><item><title>Rust 2020</title><link>https://www.ncameron.org/blog/rust-2020/</link><description><![CDATA[I'll start by arguing in favour of an edition in 2021. Then I will indulge in some rumination on the nature and necessity of roadmaps. Finally I'll make some probably obvious points in a long-winded way. Tl;dr, money is a thing we need to think about, async programming and WASM are important, and the compiler should be faster. For good measure, I will re-open a can of worms concerning the standard library.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc4dd0c3-6f8b-4450-b779-7ed4f60024a0</guid><pubDate>Mon,  4 Nov 2019 20:24:52 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Nick Cameron</dc:creator></item><item><title>My share on Rust 2020</title><link>https://dev.to/augustocdias/my-share-on-rust-2020-27m8</link><description><![CDATA[Some weeks ago the rust-lang team made a blog post asking for opinions on what the priorities for the next year should be. It really amazes me how the team hears everybody and how friendly the community is.

I have been learning rust for more than a year already, but this year was the first where I tried to write something real and production ready with it. I've gotta say I had a lot of ups and downs with it, but I'm still amazed by the language and its ecosystem. ]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">b42bc892-2146-4ac9-b2a1-5e1536abcddc</guid><pubDate>Mon,  4 Nov 2019 12:14:01 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Augusto</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust 2020</title><link>https://thomashartmann.dev/blog/rust-2020/</link><description><![CDATA[In which I respond to the recent call for blogs put out by the Rust core team and write down my wishes for Rust in 2020. Yup, GATs and const generics are there, but also slice patterns and a request for better documentation around async development.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e31e9ad-357b-4a9a-b76b-fe8c5b5e993a</guid><pubDate>Mon,  4 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Thomas Hartmann</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust 2020: Discoverability</title><link>https://apiraino.github.io/2019/11/04/call-for-2020-roadmap.html</link><description><![CDATA[Here we come with the "Request for Comment" about Rust for the next 2020 year. I'm sure 2020 will be a great year, also because it's easy and fast to write :) My wishlist will be short and to the point. Looking back to what I wished for 2019 I'd like first to see what has changed, from my point of view.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2c358d7-aae8-4cb8-93ac-edfaa975072b</guid><pubDate>Mon,  4 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><dc:creator>apiraino</dc:creator></item><item><title>My Rust 2020 wish list: playing nice</title><link>https://blog.dend.ro/my-rust-2020-wishlist/</link><description><![CDATA[This year I decided to jot down some thoughts for the Rust 2020 call for blog posts. I think the general theme here will be integration or "playing well", on different levels. A lot of these here are not language changes, and most of them already exist in some form. Probably none of them are new ideas.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">4177b33f-0805-4527-b833-259cf518761a</guid><pubDate>Sun,  3 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Laurențiu Nicola</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust 2020: Write Once, Run Anywhere</title><link>https://www.boringcactus.com/2019/11/03/rust-2020.html</link><description><![CDATA[Thing that is cool: writing the same codebase and having it run on desktop, mobile, and web thing that is lame: JavaScript is the only language where people really do that right now, outside of big commercial game engines things that need to happen for Rust to get there…]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">eeeecc4b-3e3d-43f1-b362-1fb59995d8c0</guid><pubDate>Sun,  3 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Melody Horn</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust 2020: Generics &amp; cargo features</title><link>https://blog.turbo.fish/rust-2020/</link><description><![CDATA[This is my personal wishlist of things I'd like to see in 2020 relating to Rust. It only contains technical items, not because I disagree with the people who say we should prioritize some non-technical things, but because I feel like I don't have much of value to add to that topic.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c81b74e-4e60-42e9-961d-be0ebb810c87</guid><pubDate>Sat,  2 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jonas Platte</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust 2020: what about feedbacks?</title><link>https://blog.guillaume-gomez.fr/articles/2019-11-01+Rust+2020%3A+what+about+feedbacks%3F</link><description><![CDATA[I've been working on the Rust compiler for years. It got stabilized, then matured through the years. From my point of view, it now has most of the features I wanted. So what would I want for Rust 2020 and what's coming after? To sum it up: feedbacks.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">15458bd0-19bb-4bf6-8460-5857ec6aecdc</guid><pubDate>Fri,  1 Nov 2019 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Guillaume Gomez</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust 2020 - Libraries, Libraries, Libraries!</title><link>https://beyermatthias.de/blog/2019/11/01/rust-2020-libraries-libraries-libraries/</link><description><![CDATA[The call for blogs was just issues a few days ago - and here I am writing about my biggest pains this year… because that’s what the call for blogs basically is for me… I write down my pains with Rust and hope things get better slowly next year.

Don’t misunderstand what I want to say here though: Rust is awesome, has an awesome community, awesome tooling, awesome everything… well not completely (because otherwise I wouldn’t have to write this article, right?]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">702fd8df-1263-4a2b-ae50-ea9b5e27e35a</guid><pubDate>Fri,  1 Nov 2019 20:45:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Matthias Beyer</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust 2020: A better ecosystem</title><link>https://omarabid.com/rust-2020</link><description><![CDATA[I’m fairly new to Rust, and thus my perspective is that of someone who is not quite sophisticated with the language. I think Rust is hard to learn but should be manageable for your average software developer given enough persistence. Once you are over that barrier, you start thinking of building something in Rust. Probably, for the web, or a desktop application, or a mobile application; because that’s largely what many developers are building today.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2e770a7-f957-470a-8d0b-e5ba86c9872e</guid><pubDate>Fri,  1 Nov 2019 13:37:48 -0700</pubDate><dc:creator>Abid Omar</dc:creator></item><item><title>@notriddle&apos;s Rust 2020 wishlist, or, Rust 2021: Integration</title><link>http://txti.es/notriddle-rust-2020</link><description><![CDATA[This is just a brain dump. Doing all of this is not going to happen, but all of it is stuff I know of that impacts Rust's integration with the rest of the world and eventually becoming Too Big To Fail like C++ is.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2f9e31b-3a47-48f0-981b-0f00fe03471e</guid><pubDate>Fri,  1 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>notriddle</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust 2021: Sustainability</title><link>https://xampprocky.github.io/public/blog/rust-2021/</link><description><![CDATA[For the 2019 roadmap Jonathan Turner wrote a blog post called the The Fallow Year that posited that we should let the new designs "field" rest (go fallow) while we focus on other areas. To extend that metaphor, I would say Rust has fallen into monocropping in 2019 by focusing too much on our technical debt, when we needed to be addressing our social debt.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">5458741c-97c2-4a8f-bb9e-73daf7317c81</guid><pubDate>Fri,  1 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>XAMPPRocky</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust 2020: Let’s embrace the Eternal September</title><link>https://tim.mcnamara.nz/post/188733729327/rust-2020-lets-embrace-the-eternal-september</link><description><![CDATA[User growth means accepting people that haven’t been exposed to Rust’s norms yet. Let’s not fracture because of an argument over top-posting vs bottom-quoting or something equally trivial. We need to make sure that Rust is prepared to welcome people who are just learning about Rust today. We don’t want anyone to feel like they’re late to the party.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">05982a72-c4dd-49ff-8384-3af1783e7211</guid><pubDate>Fri,  1 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Tim McNamara</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust 2020: GUI and community</title><link>https://raphlinus.github.io/rust/druid/2019/10/31/rust-2020.html</link><description><![CDATA[In response to the call for blogs about the vision for Rust for 2020, I’m going to write about GUI. I believe the time is right for a native GUI toolkit written in Rust, and that such a thing would fill a very important niche. There is a demand for performance (which, to me, includes startup time, RAM footprint, and binary size), and Rust is in the best position to deliver on that.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6cb0f49-a174-4d58-9acd-2253bbf3bfbe</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 19:27:42 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Raph Levien</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust 2020</title><link>https://bes.github.io/guide/2019/10/31/rust-2020-call-for-blogs.html</link><description><![CDATA[We have all been called upon by @rustlang to share our thoughts on what we want from Rust in 2020. My wants are centered around the developer/debug experience more than the language itself. I find the language to be expressive and attractive for many types of development, and I find the community to be very pleasant.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">688e00b5-4286-4181-af3e-31bf8090ae74</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 17:34:11 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Erik Zivkovic</dc:creator></item><item><title>My Rust 2020 ideas</title><link>https://phaazon.net/blog/rust-2020-ideas</link><description><![CDATA[This blog article is a small reply to the public call for blog posts 2020 in the Rust community. I will express what I would like Rust to go to, keeping in mind that it’s solely my ideas and opinions others’ might differ. The points expressed here are written by decreasing priority, starting with the feature I would like the most to see implemented as soon as possible.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f06b972-507b-441b-a4ce-9fbf0cdfcf96</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Dimitri Sabadie</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust 2020</title><link>https://blog.hwc.io/posts/rust-2020/</link><description><![CDATA[Every year there’s a call for blogs reflecting on goals for Rust for the upcoming year. For me, the theme is “Community First”.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f4398a8-473f-47e8-9c7a-616caba80e6d</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 10:31:16 -0400</pubDate><dc:creator>hwc</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust 2020 reflections</title><link>https://gist.github.com/mark-i-m/a39320449a1311515ac62e43ddd9dee0</link><description><![CDATA[This year, I am quite divided due to a bunch of competing desires: I still want all of the things that I wanted last year. In particular, it would be great if OS developement could finally be done on stable rust. Things like inline asm are blocking this. I think there is still a great deal of technical debt left over. I'll talk more about this later. It's not clear what the right balance of new features and working on technical debt is.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ece4d28-616e-4ea1-b182-f194738e220f</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 14:27:23 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>mark-i-m</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust 2020</title><link>https://insanitybit.github.io/2019/10/30/rust-2020-wishlist-stabilize-the-ecosystem</link><description><![CDATA[In 2019 the big focus was async/await, or at least as an outsider that is how it has appeared. The end result looks like it will deliver what we’ve all been waiting for - efficient async code that works well with Rust’s borrow checker. As 2019 is coming to a close and async/await is stabilizing, there is the obvious question - what next?]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">071c6a14-46cc-468f-a9c7-fd456360ffe9</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>InsanityBit</dc:creator></item><item><title>My Wishes for Rust 2020</title><link>https://cetra3.github.io/blog/rust-2020/</link><description><![CDATA[2019 was another huge year for rust, but instead of implementing the shiny new thing, it's been a focus on refining existing ideas. Having being using rust professionally for over 3 years, I feel I will very soon be regailing new rust developers of the times before NLL & async, where we had to play lexicon-fu to get things like caches to work in a reasonable fashion, or using super dooper combinator chains and wrestling with futures types (Either::A/B anyone?). So I'd like to make clear my acknowledgement that I am happy with the direction that the rust language is heading in, and these requests are really nice to haves.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">96de766f-57ab-48b5-a1ad-97c4fe3d67eb</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Cetra</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust 2020: exploit dominance in web assembly and no_std</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/rust/comments/dp1omc/rust_2020_exploit_dominance_in_web_assembly_and/</link><description><![CDATA[I'm a no name who's just grateful to play around with Rust. The most exciting aspects of Rust is seeing a expressive language go where other languages can barely tread (wasm,linux kernels, microcontrollers). I hope Rust continues to be the bleeding edge tech in web assembly land. I would dream for a world where Rust team works closely with browsers and what new wasm features will drop, and Rust is first to get it. no_std, async, and alloc have added a lot of fascinating new capabilities to the wasm ecosystem, i'd love to see some aspects get stabilized in this realm.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9a47fee-f918-46f1-bd89-5ddbcbd69f32</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>u/richardanaya</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust 2020 – More Or Less</title><link>https://llogiq.github.io/2019/10/30/rust-2020.html</link><description><![CDATA[The Rust team asked for 2020 roadmap blog posts, so here goes: Let’s do more of what we’ve been doing so far.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">71a819be-cc9f-43fc-bc00-a9c182229efc</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Llogiq</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust 2020: Private enum variants</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/rust/comments/dov6ox/rust_2020_private_enum_variants/</link><description><![CDATA[For the 2021 edition of Rust, I'd like to see private enum variants.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b2c0d1d-3b43-444e-8755-e8e4a60cb2b7</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>u/joshlf_</dc:creator></item><item><title>My Rust 2020 blog post</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/rust/comments/dot5pk/my_rust_2020_blog_post/</link><description><![CDATA[The 2019 goals for the Rust project were to finish some old language and library features that have had a lot of design but have not been pushed through the finish line.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">86590c31-b27d-4d59-b6d8-23eaae5c3dac</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>u/0b_0101_001_1010</dc:creator></item><item><title>A call for blogs 2020</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/rust/comments/dorinl/a_call_for_blogs_2020/</link><description><![CDATA[Comments on the call for blog posts in 2020 on Reddit, some of which include 2020 wishes.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">a32d1a1c-6453-4222-b0a6-9a7f996f6864</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Commenters on Reddit</dc:creator></item><item><title>Vision for Rust 2020 - Integration</title><link>https://www.hardmo.de/article/2019-10-29-rust-2020-vision.md</link><description><![CDATA[With async close the completion everything looks to fall perfectly in place for maintaining the developer momentum that Rust has picked up. The language has surely shown to be approachable, flexible for new concepts and continues to be loved. So are we done? Of course not. I would like to see next years theme be Integration.]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">a11ab1b4-86e3-4200-8cea-1c5ceb185dd8</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 20:58:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Andreas Molzer</dc:creator></item><item><title>A call for blogs 2020</title><link>https://blog.rust-lang.org/2019/10/29/A-call-for-blogs-2020.html</link><description><![CDATA[We are accepting ideas about almost anything having to do with Rust: language features, tooling needs, community programs, ecosystem needs... if it's related to Rust, we want to hear about it.

One big question for this year: will there be a Rust 2021 edition? If so, 2020 would be the year to do a lot of associated work and plan the details. What would the edition's theme be?]]></description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dd9b6b4-1ab5-4421-b806-61594b0f5f98</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>The Rust Core Team</dc:creator></item></channel></rss>