<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Read Rust - Performance</title><link>https://readrust.net/</link><description>Performance posts on Read Rust</description><item><title>Speeding Up &apos;dwarfdump&apos; With Rust</title><link>https://robert.ocallahan.org/2018/03/speeding-up-dwarfdump-with-rust.html</link><description>Writing a debugger for C++ on Linux, you spend a lot of time examining pretty-printed DWARF debug information using tools like readelf, objdump or dwarfdump. Unfortunately this can be quite slow.

I decided to try to speed dwarfdump up. TL;DR: I reduced the dump time from 506s to 26s by fixing some simple issues and taking advantage of Rust &quot;fearless parallelism&quot;. I think there are interesting opportunities for speeding up many kinds of command-line tools using Rust and parallelism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3052579c-dccc-46b8-8d93-bbecfa493992</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 14:44:00 +1300</pubDate><dc:creator>Robert O&apos;Callahan</dc:creator></item><item><title>Rust + Node.js are awesome!</title><link>https://itnext.io/rust-node-js-are-awesome-a50d63411773</link><description>Blazing fast, low requirements, computationally intensive operations on Node.js using Rust</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07825eb3-aaab-46c5-b7e4-680857d73750</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 21:50:20 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Benjamín Calderón</dc:creator></item><item><title>Building a fast Electron app with Rust</title><link>https://keminglabs.com/blog/building-a-fast-electron-app-with-rust/</link><description>When I built Finda, I wanted it to be fast — specifically, to respond to all user input within 16 milliseconds.

Given this goal, you might be surprised to learn that Finda is built with Electron, a framework that’s often decried for being the opposite of fast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">655ac748-e1e9-4fa4-b12a-2dc7c2e88fa7</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate><dc:creator>Kevin J. Lynagh</dc:creator></item><item><title>Three Algorithm Optimizations Outside [Place], [Other place]</title><link>https://medium.com/@urschrei/three-algorithm-optimizations-outside-place-other-place-294de5a68f27</link><description>Recently, I came across an ad for a job that had a precondition for application: it required you to first solve a ✨programming challenge✨:</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ebef41d-c7b1-424a-a120-ebf1098bbe38</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 17:12:42 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Steph</dc:creator></item><item><title>Criterion.rs v0.2 - a statistics-driven benchmarking library for Rust</title><link>https://bheisler.github.io/post/criterion-rs-0-2/</link><description>Criterion.rs is a statistics-driven benchmarking library for Rust. It provides precise measurements of changes in the performance of benchmarked code, and gives strong statistical confidence that apparent performance changes are real and not simply noise. Clear output, a simple API and reasonable defaults make it easy to use even for developers without a background in statistics. Unlike the benchmarking harness provided by Rust, Criterion.rs can be used with stable versions of the compiler.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e5df82f-aba3-4832-bbe6-e995b2e544ef</guid><pubDate>Mon,  5 Feb 2018 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate><dc:creator>Brook Heisler</dc:creator></item><item><title>Benchmark of different Async approaches in Rust</title><link>https://vorner.github.io/async-bench.html</link><description>The story about Rust’s async is still a bit in flux. There’s a bunch of libraries with their pros and cons and different approaches. Even I’m a bit to blame for that, as I’m writing one of my own, called Corona.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ccb8993-1118-4eb4-a1fb-0c6146948662</guid><pubDate>Sat,  3 Feb 2018 11:16:55 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Michal &apos;vorner&apos; Vaner</dc:creator></item><item><title>Faster Progress Report 2</title><link>https://adamniederer.com/blog/faster-pr-2.html</link><description>faster began as a yak shave, created to aid base💯 in its quest to become the fastest meme on Github. Writing an explicit AVX2-accelerated version of base💯&apos;s encoder and decoder, then realizing I&apos;d have to do the same thing again to see the speedups on my Ivy Bridge desktop, pushed me to make this library. Months later, it has blossomed into its own project, and has eclipsed base💯 in both popularity and promise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1a29851-ab4c-4739-a41f-56e9c783f5e4</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 22:14:41 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Adam Niederer</dc:creator></item></channel></rss>